pangeamedia.com 2017-09-15

# SnapApp Privacy Policy | SnapApp

Last Updated September 16, 2016

  Your privacy is important to SnapApp, Inc. (“SnapApp”, “We”, “Us”). This Privacy Policy applies to the SnapApp website: [www.snapapp.com](http://www.snapapp.com/) and Software Platform. Information collection, use and protection of personally identifiable information, including but not limited to name, email address and phone number ("PII") and the choices you have concerning PII are described in this policy. By using the SnapApp website and software platform you consent to the practices described in this policy. SnapApp is located at 222 Berkeley Street, 8th Floor, Boston, MA, 02116. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Client has engaged SnapApp.

SnapApp participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.  SnapApp is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List. <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>

SnapApp is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf.  SnapApp complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, SnapApp is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.  In certain situations, SnapApp may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Via our software platform, SnapApp provides technology and services to our customers that enable them to engage with end users through the creation and deployment of Applications. If we collect information (including PII) of our customers through our Applications, this Privacy Policy applies to that collection of information. If, on the other hand, our customers collect information from their end users through our Applications, this Privacy Policy does not apply to that collection of information. This is because SnapApp is only collecting information under the direction of its customers and has no direct relationship with our customers' end users, and does not control our customers' collection and/or use of the end users' information. To learn how a SnapApp customer (the data controller) uses the information it collects in this way, please see that customer's privacy policy. To access data controlled by our customers, if you are an end user who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data, or if you are an end user of one of our customers and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our customers that use our Service please contact them directly. If requested to remove data we will respond within a reasonable timeframe. We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our Service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the Service agreements with our Clients.

We regularly review our compliance with this Policy. SnapApp may edit this Policy from time to time and in the event the policy is revised we will notify you by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective of any significant/material change. Please direct any questions or concerns regarding this Policy via email to [theprivacygroup@snapapp.com](mailto:theprivacygroup@snapapp.com).

**I. Collected Information**

Registration Information: Registration is required to create SnapApp applications or purchase the SnapApp Service. You will be asked for PII as part of the registration process. SnapApp requires that account holders be eighteen (18) years of age or older.

Marketing Information: In addition we collect information at our site and through SnapApp Applications that we use for marketing to current and prospective customers. Additional information collected through our use of SnapApp Applications may include responses to questions.

Payment Information: Credit Card and direct debit payments for SnapApp are processed through a third party payment processing provider. SnapApp does not store your personal Credit Card information. For payments requiring an invoice rather than credit card or direct debit, SnapApp will store billing information, such as name and billing address.

Other Information: In addition to PII, additional information may be collected, such as system information, browser type (e.g., Netscape, Internet Explorer, Firefox), IP address, the type of operating system you are using (e.g., Windows or Mac OS), what version of Adobe Flash you are using (e.g., Flash 9.0), CPU type (e.g. Pentium), your manner of connecting to the Internet (e.g., connection speed through narrowband or broadband access), and the domain name of your Internet service provider and stored in log files. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.  We and our marketing partners, affiliates, or analytics or infrastructure service providers, use technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts, to analyze trends, administer the website, tracking users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual and aggregated basis. In addition, SnapApp uses third-party service provider partners to employ anonymous cookies for analytical, accounting and data integrity purposes.

Behavioral Targeting: We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this website and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

Local Storage: We use Local Storage, such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity also use Flash cookies or HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5. To manage Flash cookies, please click here:[http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/sett...](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html)

Other sources: We may receive information about you from other sources, including publicly available information or information available from third party sources, such as updated delivery and address information from our carriers or third parties, and add it to our account and marketing database information, generally for updating purposes. We may also obtain information about you through optional co-registration and/or advertisements on sites operated by third parties.

Cookies: Our Site uses Cookies, which are pieces of data stored in the browser's memory or written to the user's hard drive that provide the ability to recall information across user sessions. This also enables tracking of various user actions, including across other web sites over time, and helps customize the display of site content. Most web browsers are automatically set to accept cookies. SnapApp sites will not work correctly if cookies are disabled, and some functionality may be completely unavailable. You may reset your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie or to reject cookies generally. The Help menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable cookies altogether.

Other website related Information: Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of SnapApp. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any Web site you visit. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. Our Web site may offer publicly accessible message boards, blogs, and community forums. Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through SnapApp public message boards, blogs, or forums, this information may be collected and used by others. To request removal of your personal information from our testimonial, blog or community forum, contact us at [theprivacygroup@snapapp.com](mailto:theprivacygroup@snapapp.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

Social Media Widgets: Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button, and Widgets, such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs that run on our website. These Features may collect your Internet protocol address, which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it.

SnapApp's Web site currently does not respond to "do not track" or similar signals.

**II. Use of Collected Information**

Marketing: By submitting PII to SnapApp you grant SnapApp the right to use that information for marketing purposes, such as contacting you about new features and promotions offered by SnapApp.

Your PII is also used in a variety of other ways, including:

  * Provisioning your use of the SnapApp software platform
  * Ensuring better presentation of site content to match demographic interests
  * Contacting you regarding your SnapApp account, and confirming your registration with SnapApp
  * Tracking your compliance with the SnapApp Master Service Agreement
  * Improving content and acquiring feedback

**III. Information Sharing and Disclosure**

We share your personal information with other companies so that they can market their products or services to you. If you do not want us to share your personal information with these companies, contact us at [theprivacygroup@snapapp.com](mailto:theprivacygroup@snapapp.com). We also share PII with other companies or individuals outside of SnapApp in the following limited circumstances:

Third Party Service-Providers: SnapApp may from time to time share email addresses and other PII with third parties to perform functions on our behalf, such as sending informational emails about our products and services, lookup and reference, data enhancement, suppression, and validation. In these cases, SnapApp uses only trusted partners who are prohibited from using your information except to provide services for and on behalf of SnapApp and are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

Protection of SnapApp and others: In certain situations, SnapApp may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We reserve the right to access, use, preserve or disclose PII: as required by law, regulation, legal process or governmental request and when we believe that access, use, preservation or disclosure is necessary to protect our or our users' rights, property or safety and / or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, legal process or governmental request served upon our company; enforce the terms and conditions of SnapApp, including investigation of potential violations; and to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues.

Non-Personally Identifiable Information: We may share, publish or disseminate aggregated, non-personally identifiable information about our users, such as reports we publish about overall usage of SnapApp. This information may include demographics, usage, or characteristics of SnapApp participants as a group.

Merger/Acquisitions: If SnapApp becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of its assets, we will provide notice before PII is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

**IV. Access to Information and Preferences/Opt-Out**

Upon request SnapApp will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information.  To request this information please contact us at [theprivacygroup@snapapp.com](mailto:theprivacygroup@snapapp.com).    
If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer to desire our Service, you may correct, update, and/or request deletion on our site at<https://manage.snapapp.com/profile> or by emailing us at [theprivacygroup@snapapp.com](mailto:theprivacygroup@snapapp.com). If you request that your user information be deleted from our records, there may be a brief delay in our processing that request, while we verify that the request is valid and originates from you as opposed to an unauthorized third party. If you request that your information be deleted, we reserve the right to terminate and/or limit your access to the SnapApp website and services. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

We will retain your information, and on behalf of our customers, for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.  
To the extent we use PII to email you about our products and services, our email practices are in compliance with the U.S. laws. We also provide you the opportunity to opt out of having your PII used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication, or by emailing us at [theprivacygroup@snapapp.com](mailto:theprivacygroup@snapapp.com). We offer an opportunity to opt out of certain communications at <http://info.snapapp.com/UnsubscribePage.html>. If you do opt out from receiving promotional communications from us, this does not prohibit us from sharing PII for non-marketing purposes listed above.

**V. Security**

No method of safeguarding information is 100% secure. SnapApp uses a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your PII from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. SnapApp maintains the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When sensitive personal information is collected on our site and/or transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

**VI. California Privacy Rights**

California law allows California residents to ask companies with whom they have an established business relationship to provide certain information about the companies' sharing of personal information with third parties for direct marketing purposes. SnapApp does not share any California consumer personal information with third parties for marketing purposes without consent.

California customers who wish to request further information about our compliance with this law or have questions or concerns about our privacy practices may contact us using the contact information set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**VII. International Visitors**

SnapApp's Site is hosted and operated in the United States ("US"). By using the Site, you are consenting to the transfer of your personal information to the US. If you are accessing this Site from outside the US, please be advised that US law may not offer the same privacy protections as the law of your jurisdiction.

**VIII. Children**

SnapApp account holders must be 18 years of age. We employ commercially reasonable measures to prevent the creation of SnapApp accounts by minors under the age of 18, and to terminate accounts found to be in violation of this policy. SnapApp does not knowingly collect personal information from minors under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, please do not provide us with your personal information. If you have reason to believe that a child has provided us with their personal information, please contact us at [theprivacygroup@snapapp.com](mailto:theprivacygroup@snapapp.com) and we will delete that information from our databases.

SnapApp is not responsible for information obtained from underage users who have provided false information regarding their age. However, in these instances, parents may contact SnapApp at [theprivacygroup@snapapp.com](mailto:theprivacygroup@snapapp.com) and have his/her information removed.

**IX. Contact Information**

SnapApp, Inc.  
222 Berkeley Street, 8th Floor, Boston, MA, 02116  
Email: [theprivacygroup@snapapp.com](mailto:theprivacygroup@snapapp.com)
